Jayant +91-8449229199 Jayantphor143@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Data scientist with around 3 years of industry experience in BFSI domain with wide range of functions including predictive modelling, credit risk modelling, text classification and executing data-driven solution to increase efficiency; utilize my prioritization skills and analytical ability to achieve goals of the company.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages	R, Python, SQL
Frameworks	Flask, Apache Spark, Azure, AWS (Beginner),
	Pycaret
Tools	RStudio, Anaconda Suite, MS Office (Word, PowerPoint, Excel)
Machine Learning	Statistics, XG Boost, LightGBM (GBDT & GOSS), Neural Network, Conjoint Analysis, Logistic Regression, Linear Regression, Decision Tree, Gradient Boosting, Lasso Regression, Ridge Regression, NLP

EXPERIENCE

Fiserv Bangalore

Domain: Banking Associate, Data Science Trainee, Data Analyst

July2019 – Present July2018 – June2019

- Developed an **ensemble** model framework by combining **LGBM & XGBoost model** results(using voting) to identify merchant willingness for accepting loan from Fiserv using features like fico, transaction history etc.
- Designed and implemented **XGBoost** (**Gain**, **Cover**) model to predict the merchant attrition rate and also tried the different models on **Pycaret** framework to solve the same business problem.
- Designed and implemented **ANN** (**Neural Network**) model and Garson algorithm to predict mortgage cross sell propensity.
- Built **Lasso-Ridge and Elastic net model** for detecting fraudulent activities on the cheque transactions at the processing stage.
- Designed survey questionnaire choice set addressing singularity, business restrictions and efficiency.
- Developed a **multi-logit model** for **conjoint analysis** to analyze the importance of different features and attributes of different products.
- Developed a logistic model for deposit growth to predict customers propensity to accept deposit
 product.
- Implemented **next best product** recommendation for deposit products using multinomial regression models and worked on **Market Basket Analysis** for the same using **Apriori** algorithm.
- Developed an algorithm using various machine learning and **NLP techniques** like SVM, GBM, kNN etc. to classify the survey comments into multiplesegments.
- Built a customized algorithm (using Levenshtein distance) in **Pyspark** to identify the merchant possessing the same identity with different outlets or business names.

• Developed a **credit risk modelling** framework by analyzing credit rating from various Credit rating agencies and also proposed a new rating structure based on various factors like Probability of default, risk score etc.

EDUCATION

University of Petroleum and Energy Studies

Dehradun

B. Tech in Computer Science (Business Analytics & Optimization)

2014-2018

ACHIEVEMENT

• Received level 4 award titled 'Inspire and achieve excellence' for the Year 2018.